http://www.poseidoncharters.com/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
Poseidon Charters knows how important it is to keep any information we collect about you safe. How we collect your information and what we use your information for is detailed in this Privacy Policy.
Personal information we collect from you
We acquire personal details from you in the following ways:
while completing our online booking enquiry form you give us your name, email address, state and country
when you make a request to receive our newsletter you give us your name, email address, province, state and country
when you ask us to call you back you provide your telephone number
if you request a quote by email, you provide us with your email address
if you meet us at a show or presentation, you provide us with your email address if you want us to follow up with you
if you pay by credit card you provide your details to us over the phone
when you book a trip with us, you will be asked for your passport number in order to be a passenger aboard any sailing, motor or cruise vessel
when you book a trip you will be asked to provide next of kin contact information on our waiver form
How we use your information
your email information will be added to our marketing database if you opt-in on our newsletter, booking enquiry forms or at a boat show
booking and payment documents will be stored in a secure environment for up to seven-years in accordance with Canadian accounting laws
Sharing your information
We do not share your information with any third parties. If your trip is with a third party operator, the amount of information we share with the third party operator will be shared under a verbal agreement of confidentiality and will only be information that is deemed necessary to complete the booking of your trip such as your name, passport number and next of kin details. Your email address or credit card information will not be shared with anyone.
Using your information for marketing
Poseidon Charters sends out a newsletter with information that may be of interest to you such as special offers, new sailing programs, upcoming events and news. When you provide us with your email address and opt-in on our forms, you are giving us permission to contact you in this way.
How often we will contact you for marketing
We will send out our newsletter no more than 6 times per year. If you do not want to receive our newsletter anymore, or have decided it is not of interest to you, you can opt out at any time when you receive the newsletter. You can also let us know by email or mail that you wish to unsubscribe: info@poseidoncharters.com
Poseidon Charters 1246 Bayview Drive, Woodlawn, Ontario, Canada, K0A 3M0.
How do we store and protect your information?
All personal correspondence we have with you will be saved securely on our office local computers which are not accessed via public servers. Booking paper documents are stored in private, secure offices. Our website has an SSL certificate so when you complete a booking enquiry this is private. Any information supplied to us over email cannot be acknowledged by us as to be 100% safe so we request that you consider this when sending us personal information.
How long do we store your information
Your email address will be stored until you opt out or unsubscribe out of our database online system. If you have booked a trip with us, booking documents outside of your email address are retained the length of time that we are legally required to store for accounting and audit purposes. This information will include all email correspondence, paper invoices and address details. To comply with Canadian accounting polices, we keep any booking information we hold about you which includes your address information for a period of seven years. After this period your information will be securely destroyed.
Credit card security
Poseidon Charters understands the obvious concerns you have about entering your credit card online and at this time we do not offer an e-commerce site or accept credit card payments online. We use third party encrypted software to process your credit card payments and have to sign a form of compliance once a year agreeing to our security policies. We will not use your credit card details for anything other than to fulfill payment of your trip. We store your credit card information only to complete the booking process. We will ensure that:
all information will be kept confidential and then destroyed when the trip is fulfilled
all credit card details are taken over the telephone and not over the internet
Cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences. We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used through such software as Google Analytics.  This helps us analyse data about webpage traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system. Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
How to find out what information we store about you
At anytime, you can ask to see the personal information we have on our records about you, including any correspondence we have had with you. To collect this information for you, we charge a nominal administration fee of $20. You can request this information by writing to: Poseidon Charters 1246 Bayview Drive, Woodlawn, Ontario, Canada, K0A 3M0.
Contacting us
If you have any concerns about the Poseidon Charters Privacy Policy or feel that we are not adhering to the provisions set out here, please do not hesitate to contact us by writing to: Poseidon Charters 1246 Bayview Drive, Woodlawn, Ontario, Canada, K0A 3M0. Alternatively you can email us at info@poseidoncharters.com
Disclaimer
We will securely store your email address and will not share with anyone, but we cannot be held responsible for any information you disclose in public areas of the Poseidon Charters facebook, twitter, instagram or pinterest pages.
Changes to this privacy policy
To improve our Privacy Policy, we may amend it at any time.
Ready to set sail?
Your charter experts for yacht and by the cabin charters in Greece, Croatia and French Polynesia. Over
25 years’ experience and recognized by the Greek National Tourist Organization US and Canadian offices.
WE ACCEPT:
Poseidon Charters | 1246 Bayview Drive | Woodlawn | Ontario | K0A 3M0 | Canada
Poseidon Charters Inc is a Canadian Federal Chartered Company
Company Registration 3568792
powered by webfuel
Poseidon News
Sign-up for our newsletter for exclusive charter information, offers, sailing tips and much more!
SUBSCRIBE
This website uses cookies to ensure you get the best experience on our website. Learn more.
Got it!
